limited's Q3 and 9mon fy2 24 earnings
conference
call from the Senior Management we have
with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr gopal balachandran
CFO and
cro Mr alok Agarwal executive
director Mr Girish nyak Chief technology
and health underwriting and
claims and Mr sandep Goran
Chief corporate solutions
group please note that any statements or
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr sanjie mantri MD and CEO of ICICI
Lombard General Insurance Limited thank
you and over to you sir thank you good
evening to each one of you thank you for
joining the earnings conference call of
icsa Lombard for quarter 3 and 9 month
Financial year
2024 I would like to wish you and your
family a great 2024
ahead while we had a brief interraction
in the last quarter I'm happy and
excited to engage with you all in my new
role I would like to take the first few
minutes to share my vision on the
journey ahead for our company
I firmly believe we're in the midst of
exciting times both as a country and as
an
industry India is expected to be the
fastest growing economy globally
Insurance sector is a in a country
continues to provide a multi-decadal
growth opportunity supported by the
regulatory commitment to enable
insurance for all by
2047 in my view this will unleash
tremendous positives for the industry in
time to come
as a company we will continue to create
newer value tools in the industry and
maximize our participation in the
existing ones and I believe we can
achieve this through our vision of one
Isis one
team now let me give you a brief
perspective on our vision of one is one
team over the years the company has
created multiple function
team to access various business
opportunities available
this was an approach which worked well
for us in that phase of a journey
however the present scenario is fast
evolving and dynamic due to which the
existing way of functioning inhibites us
from leveraging the combined strength of
the organization keeping this in mind we
have decided to bring a conscious shift
in a core philosophical approach we a we
aim to transcend functional silos and
convert the entire organization into a
United Team working towards a single
organization
purpose simply put it implies when icsa
Lombard wins everyone wins this will be
a cold cultural anchor and every
decision that we take whether strategic
or tactical will be guided by this I'm
excited to share that they have already
taken early steps to align our
organization to this in letter and
spirit however as we embark on this
journey we will continue to focus on
Market opportunity and leverage our
existing distribution Channel
we have over the years followed a
customer Centric approach and will
continue with our overarching philosophy
of balancing growth and
profitability let me now give you a
brief overview of the industry Trends
and developments that we have witnessed
in the past few months for this our CFO
Mr gopal balachandran will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter and 9 months ended December
31st
2023 domestic GDP GR by 7.6% during
quarter September 38th 2023 indicating
strong growth primally driven by the
government infrastructure P hethy
balance sheets of Banks and corporates
improving business sentiments and Rising
public and private care should Bo boost
capex activity going forward broader
economic activity indicators like GST
collection eway builds generation
manufacturing PMI non food credit growth
indicate robust demand in the economy
however the headman for domestic growth
can emerge from weak external demand TI
Financial conditions and geopolitical
tension as we speak India is globally
the fastest growing auto market and is
the third largest in terms of sales
volume as per cm in 9 month 2024 new
Private Car Sales Contin to have robust
growth despite the higher base with over
3.1 million Vehicles being sold mainly
driven by F festive demand
for 9 month
2024 13.5 million two wheelers were sold
also held by upti in rural demand for
the full year the sales are expected to
cross three covid
levels for 9 month Financial 2024 1.2
million commercial vehicles were sold
this was driv by growth in insire and
other core
sectors health insurance continued to
deliver robust growth remaining the
largest contributor to overall industry
premium
the commercial lines of business witness
growth in the line with Comm current
market environment further private and
public effects inv World investment have
led to rubber's growth in the
engineering line of business we expect
the commercial line segment to do well
in the future on back of overall
economic growth and capacity
creation Now speaking of the performance
The General insurance industry delivered
a Yi growth gross direct premium income
growth 14% for 9 month 2024 excluding
crop and Mass health the growth is at
15.2% for the same period overall the
combined ratio of the industry was at
11.9% for H1
2024 as against 11 12.2% for H1 2023
excluding the impact of B areas for the
Phu
Insurance within the industry the
industry combin issue for motor business
119.4 for X1 of 2024 as against 123.5
for X1 of 2023 while the Improvement in
Combined ratio is directionally positive
it continues to remain at elevated
levels further for 9 month 2024 the
industry has witnessed three catastroph
events which is expected to have an
impact on financial year 2024 industry
combined
ratio moving to business impact for us
in quarter three and 9 months for
2024 the company grew at 13.4% during Q3
of
2024 which was higher than the industry
growth of
12.3% for 9 month 2024 our growth was
16.5% against the industry growth of
14% I will now speak about the
performance in key business segments
during the quarter ended 9 month
Financial year
2024 in the commercial line of business
we have developed strong capabilities on
the back of a unique distribution
franchise duly completed comp
complemented by our value added services
this Bas underwriting and large and
highly rated reinsurance capacities as a
result we have Consolidated our Market
position in this business over the last
decade during quarter 3 Financial year
2024 we grew at 12.5% as an industry
growth of
13.3% for 9 month Financial year 2024 we
have grown by 15.7% which was higher
than the industry average of
99.7% motor as a category has always
been a focus area for us as we speak for
the first 9 months we are the second
largest motor insurer for quarter 3 we
achieved an industry leading position in
this segment we have a robust reserving
philosophy which is demonstrated by our
reserving triangles and granular data
for our portfolio decisions we'll
continue to leverage a strong
multi-distribution structure which
enables us to access the market along
with the best inclass claim servicing
teams focusing on superlative customer
experience for the motor segment and
quarter 3 they registered a growth of
5.6% as against industry growth of 10%
for 9 month Financial year 2024 we grew
at 7.1% as the industry growth of
14.3% the growth in motor segment was
headed by strong growth in the new
Private Car segment which view at 30%
for 9 months two- wheer growth of 9
months 2024 was 14% which was higher
than the CM volume growth of
99.9% as the rural demand picks up we
hope to see the trend
continue the CV segment as we had
mentioned in our earlier call had no TP
price high for financial year 2024 and
consequently we focused on targeted
portfolio sing among the available value
pools for 9 month 2024 our mix of
Private Car two wheer and CD stands at
51.4
27.8% and 20.8%
respectively we also continue to build
efficiency in motor claims in quarter 3
2024 through our preferred partner
Network we have been able to service 67%
of our agency and direct claims up from
51% in quartery financial year
2023 we are excited about the
opportunity the Mot segment and we
leverage all our existing capabilities
as one team to carry the momentum in the
coming quarter the health segment
continued to be the fastest growing
segment for the industry we grew faster
than the industry both in Q3 and 9
months registering a growth of 24.7% and
29.1%
respectively our health
business retail Health business grew in
line with the industry at 19.2% for 9
month 2024 to create a sustainable
portfolio we are focusing on preferred
geography and higher some insured our
new business grew at 24.5% during this
period why why we would have like to
grow faster we will continue to invest
by focusing on prer segment and new
product launches in the coming
quarter on Bank we have developed an
industry leading practice which
continues to be a strong pillar for our
company our bank insurance and key
relationship GR G at
13.6% for the quarter and 21.5% for 9
month
2024 we'll continue to deep mine our
existing Relationships by creating new
value streams which at the same time
focusing on acquiring a new relationship
within this I say within this IC group
distribution view
19.9% for quarter 3 and 16.9% for 9
months onetop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs I take care app has
suppressed surpassed 8.5 million user
downloads till date we continue our
growth momentum with 1.6 million user
downloads for the quarter and during the
quarter Source premium was over 100
billion sorry 1 million through this app
registered a 3.2x increased
Yi our digital business Drew at 39.1% in
quarter 3 and 43% in 9 months and
constitut
6.6% and 5.8% respectively of overall
business numbers it would continue to
continue to be the key growth driver for
us as I look ahead I'm personally very
excited with this opportunity and
committed to creating long-term
sustainable value for all our
stakeholders now I would request gopal
to take you through the financial
numbers for the Recently concluded
quarters and nine months thanks a and uh
good evening to all I will now give give
you a brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months we have uploaded
the results presentation on our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers gross direct
premium income of the company was at
r7.3 billion in 9 months FY 24 as
against R 16.48% FY 23 this was a growth
of 16.5% which was higher than the
industry growth of
14% excluding propop and Mass health
gdpi growth of the company was at 15
.6% it was higher than the industry
growth of 15.2% in 9 months
f24 GDP was at 62.3 billion in Q3 f524
as against R 44.93 billion in Q3 fi23 a
growth of
13.4% this growth was higher than the
industry growth of
12.3% excluding crop and mass sales gdpi
growth was at 12% which was again higher
than the industry growth of 11.3% in 9
months
F4 our GDP growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall GDP of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 12.5% at 16 billion in Q3 fi 24 as
against 14.22 billion in Q3
fi23 on the retail side of the business
GDP of the motor segment was at R
28.425b in Q3 fi23 registering a growth
of
5.6% the advance premium numbers was was
Ates 33.4 billion at 31st December 2023
as against rupes
32.892880
billion in Q3 fi23 registering a growth
of
24.7% our agent which includes a point
of sale distribution count was 1
12588 as on December 31 2023 up from 1ak
22461 as on September 30 2023 GDP of the
retail Health segment grew by 16.2%
during the quarter three Group Health
segment grew by 27.2% during Q3 fi
24 as against last year where we saw no
major catastrophic events during the
year during this year we witnessed three
major catastrophes Cyclone paperjoy
North Indian floods and Cyclone mang our
share of insured losses in these scat
events have been lower than our natural
market share resultantly combined ratio
was 103.7 for 9 month f524 as against 10
14.6% for 9 months
fi23 excluding the impact of Gat losses
of rupees 1.37 billion in 9 months f524
the combined ratio was 10
12.6% combined ratio was 103.6 in Q3 fi
24 as against 10
14.4% in Q3
fi23 again excluding the impact of cash
losses of .54 billion rupees in Q3 fi 24
the combined ratio was 10
12.3% our investment assets Rose to
rupes 4686 7 billion as at December 31
2023 from rupes 43.122762
25.96 billion in 9 months f524 as
against rep 21.6 billion in 9 months f23
on a quarterly basis investment income
was at 8.38 billion in Q3 f524 as
against rupes 7.66 billion in Q3
fi23 our capital gains net of impairment
on investment assets stood at R 3.95
billion in 9 months
f524 as compared to rupes 2.94 billion
in 9 months
fi23 capital gain net of employment
investment assets stood at rupees 1.08
billion in quarter 3 fi 24 as against
1.52 billion rupees in Q3
fi23 our profit before tax grew by 20.6%
at rupes 18.5 57 billion in 9 months
f524 as against rupes 15.4 billion in 9
months fi23 whereas PBT grew by 23.3% at
rupes 5.74 billion in Q3 f524 as against
R 4.65 billion in Q3 f52
consequently profit after tax grew by
8.3% at R 13.99 billion in 9 months fi
24 as against rupes 12.92%
fi23 excluding the impact of tax
reversal provision in quarter 2 of
fi23 fat grew by 20.2% in 9 months
f24 fat grew by 22.4% at rupes 4.31
billion in Q3 fi 24 up from rupees 3.53
billion in Q3 fi23
return on average Equity was 17.1% in 9
month f524 as against 18.1% in 9 month
fi23 the return on Equity average equity
for quarter 3 f524 was
15.3% as against 14.3% in Q3 fi23
solvency ratio was at 2.57 times at
December 31 2023 as against 2.59 times
at September 30 2023 this continued to
be higher than the regulatory minimum of
1.5 times as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safeguarding interest
of policy holders at all times I would
like to thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may
have thank you we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on their Touchstone telephone if
you wish to withdraw yourself from the
question queue you may press star and
two participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question ladies
and gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question Q
assembles the first question is from the
line of kishan Runa from MK Global
please go
ahead kishan your line has been unmuted
you may proceed with your
question
kishan runta your line has been
unmuted as there's no response from the
current participant we will proceed to
the next question which will be from the
line of Shrea
Shivani from clsa please go ahead thank
you for the opportunity uh
congratulation on a good set of members
I have uh two question questions uh so
firstly uh excluding all the calamities
that we have seen in 9 month your
combined ratio has come at
102. 3% right and we had earlier given a
guidance to reach 102% by fi25 end so
clearly a much better growth in new
vehicle sales has supported lower loss
ratios this year uh so can you help us
understand what is your revised guidance
for the next year or next two years on
the combined ratio side given that uh we
know that you are currently investing in
the health portfolio and on technology
front Etc so that'll be the first
question and the second question sir can
you quantify the loss ratio trend for
retail health and Group Health and uh
there have been some covid cases uh in
the southern part of the country how
many cases do you have is it something
that we should be concerned about for
the fourth quarter for the next quarter
just trying to understand if there's yet
another thing that hits Us in the next
quarter
okay I think thanks
sh as far as the combined is show
guidance is concerned uh then uh gopal
will share with you in detail the loss
issues that you're seeking on the retail
as well as the group health side uh uh
clearly uh we stick to the guideline of
what we mentioned that will go to 102
over a period of time uh in terms of
revision clearly from an industrial
standpoint again we are seeing uh
ourselves Place reasonably well but does
this need to make us believe the
guideline can go through a change at
this point we would say we hold to this
we want to see this trend holding up
over next maybe a quarter or two and
then we'll come back to the market if
you believe there a revision uh to be
done on
that uh in terms of retail and ghx
trending by this we have seen
improvement over what we had seen over
last goal will share the numbers in
details yeah sh so I think uh so if you
look at the uh
this is employer employee or let's say
the group health loss ratios for quarter
three of last year that number was
98.9% this year quarter three that
number stands at about
93.1 uh on a 9 Monon basis the again the
ghi loss ratios for last year was
95.9% 9 months of the current year that
number is at
95.8 on retail Indemnity again in the
same order Q3 last year was 68% Q3 this
year is at
66% uh this is pretty much in line with
the range that we have been talking
about which is in the range of between
65 to 70% is the threshold that we are
comfortable with on the retail Indemnity
side and on the 9 Monon basis again
retail Indemnity loss ratios last year
was at 65.2 this year we are at about
65.6% uh so that's the breakdown in
terms of the loss ratio across different
segments to your last point on uh covid
claims uh intimations I think too early
at this point of time we don't see any
specific uh instances or any spikes that
we get to see obviously we will watch
for the development but nothing at this
point of time for us to call out as of
now no cause of
concern okay sure and the overall
combined ratio guidance I got get it
right that you may come back to us after
maybe a quarter or two if there's any
change in the guidance for now it's 102
point 102% for fi25 yeah right now it's
102 we're not it but as I said seeing
how the other qu for will come back
probably by the year end sure sure this
is useful thank you so much thank you
thank you thank you the next question is
from the line of sankit godam from
avendus spark please go
ahead yeah yeah thank you for the
opportunity uh sanj we are seeing a
little better Trend in motor especially
in the month of November and December
compared to the industry so so just
wanted to understand that our strategy
with respect to motor has little changed
probably we are seeing little growth
coming back is it because of the pricing
environment changing or or we believe we
will be a little more uh aggressive or
more confident to do motor than than
what we were doing in the past that's
that's my first question and and and on
similar lines uh again again in the
third quarter if I see you seems to have
grown Health retail Health especially at
a lower rate compared to the industry
despite doing Investments um we we
thought that you will grow at at least
1.2 to 1.3x of the industry your growth
seems to be broadly lower than the
industry marginally lower than industry
so so just wanted to understand uh why
the cautious stands being taken with
respect to on health or or is it because
of the competition on retail uh that
that's on growth and and and and just
just on on gopal the question is motor
TP loss ratio uh see the number seems to
be again uh very good at around 62 um
and in third quarter or 65 in in N9
months so so typically we tend to uh
boost up the reserves in in fourth
quarter that historical Trend suggest so
so so so is it a case that we will see a
similar Trend or or you believe that 65%
motor also show reported for 9 months
will sustain for the entire year and and
similarly if you can com comment on on
the motor OD to whether whether this is
this is the number what we are looking
at
65 okay uh sir I will goal will cover
the TP part I'll cover the motor what is
the trend that we are seeing and the
strategy going forward also on the
retail Health in terms of the numbers
which are relatively subdued which I
also said uh in my initial comment that
definitely would have wanted to goow
faster than that uh first thing on the
motor uh I think we continue to be a
very uh you know competent and uh
relevant player uh we saw in the past
also and we given that guidance that
whenever we have seen that kind of a
market share being shaped up it was more
conscious because the intensity uh what
we thought would get stabilized did not
happen uh so we had taken a step back
and let it flow the way it is now we
have seen some of our key competitors
who are ruling in have started uh
putting lot more method in that Madness
and that has given us an opportunity
that being said quarter 3 typically has
a tendency to have lot more new sales in
the season and there we do uh end up
with the structure that we have having a
lot more uh to you know achieve as a
team on motor overall on market share
but more importantly the very critical
Trend which can highlight to all of you
is that whyi we had been losing bit of a
market share but for the month of
December we have gained a market share
of 10.7% 10.5 last year in December so
that Trend uh is a critical one and we
are well placed in terms of what we
believe if we see this uh environment
operating in AEM we will not participate
in any uh uh crazy hunt if that's what
the market leads to every reason to
believe there will be a bit more of
sunlance and in that scenario we will
see ourselves exerting a lot more in qu
four in time to come so that's what we
have on Motor Trend badly on the retail
Health a new number uh it's it's not
something which we are very uh you know
worried but yes we would have led to
grow faster we have taken certain calls
in terms of some insure which category
of portfolio rights because again if you
know whatever health book that we write
it is for a lifetime visibility
technically and we need to hold on to
that customer we had certain early Trend
which got us concerned that being said
our new book has still grown at almost
25% and we do believe that in uh uh in
time to come with the sort of investment
that we have done with our human capital
as well as the product profile which
will also happen over next couple of
quarters from our side we would be a
potent force and the and the mission
that we have shared is is firmly on
track these are all conscious calls
which does not deter us uh in terms of a
stand uh motp ask goal to answer ter of
the details that we have sh
s my I think our response will pretty
much be on the lines is what I have been
talking even in the past uh few earnings
call um so the range within which motor
OD loss ratios will operate I think even
last quarters we have been talking about
in the range of 60 to 65% I think we
pretty much stay on course in terms of
that part of the range on the motor own
Dage site that's largely because I think
uh as an organization we are kind of
focusing a lot more in so far as uh the
claims initiatives are concerned whether
it is in the context of uh the average
claim size etc etc and therefore to that
extent I think the range that we are
comfortable with on motor Odes in the
range of 60 to 65 on motor third party I
think as we keep keep saying uh again
quarterly numbers may not be the right
way to look at but even on a 9month
basis I think the number for US stands
closer to about
25% there if collect I think the range
that we have talked about has been in
the range of 65 to 70% but that again
would be a function of what kind of a
risk selection that we do and the point
that sanjie made I think clearly as an
organization we are significantly
focusing on much more uh granulation of
data risk selection uh and so on and so
forth and therefore to that extent the
range that we would be kind of looking
at operating would be on third party
side between 65 to 70% which is why on
balance when you look at motor in the
aggregate that number should be in the
range of between 65 to 67% which if you
look at the 9 month numbers the motor at
on an aggregate basis the loss ratio
stands at about 65% for this year so the
range that you will be comfortable will
be between 65 to 67 on an aggregate
basis
the only point I would say sankit is uh
in so far as there is no specific trend
line for us in so far as Q4 being seeing
any any form of aberration I think
possibly what you referring to is maybe
couple of years back uh this is I think
Financial year 2021 if I recollect it
correct I think there was certain Court
Supreme Court judgments that had come
through in that particular year and
that's the reason why not just for IC
Lombard even at an industry level
companies had to recalibrate their uh
ultimate loss experiences and therefore
to that extent one had to take some
impact of uh strengthening of uh losses
but otherwise it is not it is not
necessary that uh we do see any kind of
an inch up in so far as third party loss
experiences are concerned so far as
quarter 4 which you referring okay no no
because I I saw a similar Trend in
fourth quarter 232 so so that's the
reason I was asking the question that
the 65 number is sustainable but you
answered that you're looking at a broad
number of 65 to 70 to to playoffs of the
motor
just just to your comment on
motor just wanted to understand you are
saying that in Market overall Market
competitive environment in motor OD the
relative madness has has come off and
and therefore Market is more conducive
than it was in the past that's the
conclusion I should make so I tell you I
think that will be a relatively sharer
conclusion but yes we do see some bit of
uh semblance overall and LR of the
industry has gone down from 93 to
and so if that is the indication yes
there's a Improvement but still if you
ask me from an overall standpoint the
industry is writing the motor portfolio
uh at a you know reasonable triple digit
of 118 119 so there is a lot more that
has to come off and even a private
sector is writing at 114
115 it's a it's a long journey uh but
what I can tell you some is that where
we stand the length through which we are
looking at the market we are reasonably
confident of a practice and we will be
able to drive value for the organization
uh uh in the current environment that is
triling uh but long-term trends have to
manifest you know that the industry
numbers come with a lag we are awaiting
the 9 month numbers for the industry to
get a sense which will be able to give
you uh closure to when the financial
year gets closed for us and that time we
can have a much more evolved discussion
on this subject perfect perfect that's
it from my thank you thank
you thank you ladies and gentlemen in
order that the management can answer
questions from all participants in the
queue we request you to please restrict
your questions to two per
participant the next question is from
the line of mukar ladda from Nama weth
please go ahead uh hi good evening uh
thank you for this opportunity and
congrat congratulations for a good
actually underwriting performance uh
clearly uh you're you seem to be
achieving your guidance sooner than
expected um so just uh you know a couple
of questions uh on the motor side so I
wanted to understand uh with how is the
implementation of the entire loss
reporting uh within 6 months time uh
time period uh how is that progress in
and uh you know what is our sort of
expectation on that and related question
on this is uh is the industry um you
know in this uh uh sort of believing
that this will get implemented and as a
result of that the competitive intensity
had had had been high or or are they
sort of looking because you know they
believe that the ultimate loss ratio
will be lower so is that uh is that the
correct way to think about it or is that
the way some industry participants are
thinking about it and acting in in in
that way and second question on your
investment yield that seems to have
dropped this quarter to some
understanding of what has actually
played out of there so uh those two
would be my questions y thanks sure I'll
I'll let gopal come in and I'll give my
comments yeah go yeah so maduk I think
on the six month law of uh limitation uh
I think as we have been kind of
indicating that matter still U is before
The Supreme Court and uh obviously we
will wait for let's see the verdict to
come out what we understand is I think
most of the states seems to be in favor
of getting the law of six months
implemented and therefore to that extent
I think one would obviously wait and see
how the final BDI it plays through but
the the direction that states want to
take is clearly to kind of get a law of
limitation in place uh having said that
what could happen let's assume for a
moment that if it goes in favor of let's
say in line with the six months law of
limitation again the impact could vary
between players in the market because at
an aggregate level for the market
obviously there will be some reduction
in frequency as we have been explaining
consequent to reduction in possible
frauds so that's a positive in so far as
the overall Market is concerned
second I think in in in the context of
IC Lombard obviously we have been
inflating uh reserves with an inflation
assumption for Isis home between 12 to
133% this inflation assumption for the
market may not be the same and therefore
to that extent whenever this will play
out the impact could be slightly more
beneficial for companies which have been
reasonable in their inflation
estimations and for us as I said we Isis
lomard has been inflating at 12 13%
Market if they have been inflating had a
slightly lower number therefore to that
extent the impact could be relatively
moderate for those set of players so
hence in that sense I think it would
obviously translate into an incremental
business opportunity for us having said
that this law of six months limitation
will be applicable only on a prospective
basis which is effective from April 1
2022 so and to that extent uh is where
we would be able to see as I said a
relative benefit playout for us in the
context of the market uh the other thing
what could also happen as a FP side to
this is in case if finally this laog
gets implemented there is a possibility
that next year or maybe in future the
regulator and the government will very
closely watch for the need for any kind
of a PP price increase uh while last
three four years again we have not
necessarily seen any kind of a
meaningful price change on the third
party side but given the fact that this
this six months law could lead to a
positive development from an overall
industry standpoint we may see periods
where we may not able to see further
increases on the third party pricing but
obviously that's a development that we
will again closely watch for in so far
as the third party uh six months law of
limitation Dynamics is concerned I'll
quickly answer the second question of
yours and then maybe I'll uh if you want
to kind of add on uh so on the
investment uh yield again mukar I think
as we have always said our Reise return
is a function of what do we see as uh
interest approval
and uh what what is it that we see as
capital gain for us uh given the fact
that we have been significantly as we've
been explaining even in the earlier
earnings calls the high interest rate
regime is something that we have
obviously taken advantage of and hence
to that extent if you would have seen
our yield to maturity on the overall
book that currently in facted December
31 stands at 7.31 per. this number if
you recollect maybe couple of few
quarters back this number was less than
7% at about 6.92% so so H to that extent
we have actually been taking advantage
of the higher interest regime and that's
kind of aing well in so far as interest
approvals are concerned where you may
possibly see in some quarters possibly a
decline in yield is consequent to let's
say maybe relatively lower levels of
capital gain that purely a function of
what we believe are Market opportunities
for any gains to be realized we have
generally not seen any instance where we
have seen uniform levels of capital
gains across Waters so in fact there
again I would urge similar to the
discussions that we have been having on
having on the loss ratio side the yield
on the overall portfolio should be
looked at again ideally over on a
financialized basis ideally over longer
years but definitely not on a quarter on
quarter basis so okay just to add mukar
in terms of the point that you mentioned
on PP directionally and we all will
agree that even when became part of
Motor Vehicle act the adoption at the
state level would have always gone
through it s but if the intent is to
make the overall consumer benefit these
things in spite of the hiccups I believe
over a period of time will get
implemented uh in a country like us it
will always be a little more complex uh
but multiple decisions which have been
taken by the body we remain positively
cautious and see that this will flow in
that direction over a period of time but
one bigger thing which I want to add
mukar is the way I has come up the
stream and improve the quality of data
sharing that can happen at the industry
level
that part has been transformative and
the level of accuracy and the the real
time manner in which we can think uh all
of the industry will benefit and we with
the with the level of you know business
that we do and that kind of an accuracy
I mean you know that banking got
transformed and Bureau came into place
and uh you could really figure out where
what stands and this data uh once it
gets created in the form will also end
up you know helping us figuring out
you know fraud and so on and so forth so
the base work has got done uh to me that
is also a big positive which can benefit
companies like a substantially to drive
efficient equation in the
market thank you m understood just one
question on the U investment book uh
what is the amount of capital
gains this time around if you could give
that versus the last
quarter uh see the number of capital
gains for the quarter three was about
108 crores that is in that is in quarter
three of this year as against 152 crores
which was the capital gains that we had
in quarter three of the last Financial
year and last quarter what was the
number sorry water two numbers uh of
capital gain that number was about
uh 164
cres okay understood problem
very clear thank you and all the best
thank you thank
you thank you the next question is from
the line of prayes Jen from Mo oswal
please go ahead uh yeah hi good evening
everyone uh just a few questions firstly
could you elaborate on your strategy
that you were talking about in your
initial opening
remarks you just elaborate on that new
philosophy that you talking
about yeah okay fair enough I'll do that
you have second question also you want
to say now which you can cover or we'll
come back once I reply on this the
second question was more on motor motor
business granularity as to you know
we've seen you know faster premium
growth with respect to as compared to
the vehicle growth and that's possibly
because of certain factors like
premiumization share of e going higher
CN chair going higher top models going
higher or you know automated Vehicles
going going higher uh any of these
cohorts where you think that the you
know particularly EVS where you know
your experience would have been kind of
uh uh you know much better than what you
would have expected earlier and you see
some price Corrections out there or in
with respect to you know drive as you
use or the the pilot project that we
were working on earlier how is that mix
evolving I think some granularity on the
motor business will help us kind of look
forward into the future on on this
business and last question was on
commission ratio where you know how do
you see the commission ratio kind of
standing out this quarter it was at 17%
there about and so how do you look at
this ratio from a fer perspective in
this okay okay thanks I think let me
give you a quick perspective of one is
one team uh I think as I also mentioned
when I spoke earlier in my script uh the
fact fact that it's a core philosophy
change uh we've been in the business for
last 22 years and obviously as an
organization we have created multiple
Center of excellences uh and these
departments have gone on to deliver a
lot more for the organization than one
could have thought at the Inception
level uh but the time has come where we
need to at an overarching level uh see
that we able to derive value at a
multiplier level for the organization to
give you an example right we we had
valuated Services which was being driv
by us as a company we have our own
patent which are registered to manage
risk but this valuated Services used to
work more on a project basis with the
entities what we have ensured is that we
getting this embedded with the
organization at multiple departments on
the commercial side to drive the impact
uh another part is on the data analytics
side you know the data Engineers we do
we do have that particular Department
which was running and quite effectively
but it was not embedded they used to
operate on a project basis what done is
that we've got ahead and got that
department working with business Chiefs
to direct reporting in terms of making
it work so there's lot of synergy
benefits that can be driven on this uh
at multiple counts we would be driving
and cross leveraging it uh our practice
as we have always mentioned on the
corporate side has been very extensive
but our ability to harness to even
procure retail business becomes a
significant part of our strategy it's
not even cross cell it's actually all
eded solution the bulk of the products
that we deal with are you know naturally
inclined towards stat requirement
whether it's on the commercial side or
motor health is the only discretionary
product uh that corporates IND in you
will also see product launches in time
to come which would be harnessing this
opportunity across the segment we l
we've got large presence but the
consolidate uh approach that was
required mind you but the word of
caution is it does not mean that the
dissecting of of the market and ensuring
that the leverage on our distribution
will get diluted uh at any point in time
for us so that's my two bit in terms of
you know discussing one is uh one team
as a as a company now coming on to the
motor part of the strategy as you see uh
uh we have seen a significant uh
transformation uh I'll just cover the
eved part of business which you spoke
about uh from an overall industry
penetration level uh it has moved 9
month the penetration was .5 it's gone
to almost
4.2 uh% for us we as a company have a
very dominant share on the EV side on
the private car which is the passengers
car we're talking about we have a market
share of almost 18% and on two- wheer we
have a market share of almost
28% uh we are obviously bullish and we
do believe that over next couple of
years we will have the inection point as
the infrastructure which is required to
see this it's getting much more uh so
two points one infrastructure other the
price point which makes it workable uh
we would continue to invest and uh loss
ratio yes we do see that uh it's
relatively better but I would not rush
to conclude that as it because these are
very early days this will emanate over a
period of time but we'll stay invested
because this is the category which can
rule the market in terms of overall
motor uh clearly quarter three new sales
which you spoke about and read those
numbers that we have seen a growth in
private car of 30% in two wheeler by
almost 14% much higher than what the
industry has done uh uh again uh
multiple things one we are well equipped
in terms of the new business as in when
that growth comes back our ability to
operate in a decisive manner uh is
pretty much their existing and we do uh
uh believe
that this should exhibit over next uh
probably a quarter or so also but we
never expected the industry on the
private car to grow at a level of almost
7 7 and a half% because the base for
last year itself was high uh and India
has moved on to become the third largest
manufacturer of uh you know overall
Motor Vehicles which itself I think
speaks about how the volumes are getting
driven another big change which has
happened is the SUV cars have started
dominating which is the average ticket
size is high so you would also see that
getting exhibited in a number uh as we
speak about the motor growth that will
come in so overall we remain uh positive
in terms of driving our motor initiative
as a team uh on the commission ratio
I'll ask gopal to just quickly give you
an update we've been pretty much within
the regulatory limit as described and
for see since the new vehicles are there
the expense ratio tends to be elevated
historically for the industry and more
so for us so PR I think again uh in line
with what we have been mentioning even
in the earlier earnings call I think a
better metric to look at as we keep
saying is combined ratios because there
will always be businesses which could be
high on LR and low on cost of
acquisition and the wi Vera as well uh
so hence to that extent I think one
would urge uh to continue to look at
more the uh combined ratios of the
company as a whole having said that I
think in line with what sanjie said if
you look at our expense of management
numbers at the percentage of gwp this
number for the 9 months last year was at
about
28.6% for the 9 months of current year
this number stands at about
28.1% so there has been some improvement
in the overall expense of Management
number but as I said a better metric to
look at is more the combined ratios for
the company as a whole uh this this
commission we request you to please
rejoin the question CU for further
questions the next question is from the
line of nides from invest Tech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity sir
first health
insurance we have been investing in that
distribution for last almost two years
but still our growth has been broadly
mind with industry or uh in the month of
December we laed industry uh so what are
the aspirations there and then we think
the the growth pick up in the retail
health insurance will in
our yeah I think a very valid question n
again as I was Mally given when I was
talking earlier in the call we also uh
would have preferred going faster uh if
you see our growth in quarter one was uh
quite higher than the industry but we
have taken certain calls on the Su inur
as well as the you know nature of new
business that we want to procure these
are very finite definite calls we are
very much on track in terms of uh what
we want to achieve uh our new business
of the SC has grown by almost
25% uh as a company so if you ask me
where will we see a real you know growth
coming in this since this changes have
been done over quarter one and quarter
two you will see this playing out uh uh
very clearly over next financial year
and what we have spoken with the market
and probably three quarters back in
terms of the growth at that point these
calibration that we have done because we
felt Health as a port folio which comes
with lifetime vity requires realtime
coration so we chose to take that call
at this point of time so that the
long-term value creation that we want
for the organization does not get
compromised uh but you will see our
convergence as a team not only in terms
of growth but also product launches
which are still uh if you ask us on a
score of 10 on product you know or
solutioning stack that we want to create
on the health side we would probably be
6 and a half and abouts over 10 as a
score we have that distance to be
covered and that also will get done in
next couple of quarters so we are very
positive and we do see good value
creation coming uh from next financial
year
onwards NES does that answer your
question yeah secondly on the motorite
our profitability has improved quite
well and our loss ratios are I think uh
one of the best that we have seen uh so
why don't we pedal we push the pedal on
the growth and uh start focusing on
market share gains in that segment even
the profitability is quite good for us I
think you have only answered the
question in terms of a we we we stayed
focused and we had some losses on market
share but we we decided to stick the
course and that's what we are doing at
this point of time uh some of the other
partners who were uh you know being
aggressive also mve down so it's a
combination of we stitching to the
course and as I was also stating uh that
December was the first month in which we
have seen a relatively better market
share in our mind uh we do believe that
quarter Force should hold good for us as
a
team okay thank you thank you that's
thank you n thank you thank you the next
question is from the line of ainash
Singh from MK Global please go ahead
yeah good evening couple of questions uh
the first one on Commercial line I mean
fire Marine engineering if I look uh on
a 9month basis the movement yui in
cleans ratio is material now uh in terms
of natcat it would have kind of a played
out maybe a bit higher this year but not
Material so now just question is that is
this sort of a clearance ratio increase
in the commercial line and outcome of
you know uh any sort of a pricing or
deteriation at the industry level or is
it also or largely due to the
reinsurance price hike that industry has
seen so I mean some color on what is
driving this commercial uh line loss
ratio increase and if the factors that I
just mentioned you know the pricing
deoration or Price He if they are
largely done this year and should
improve going forward next year that's
one second again or going on Health uh
you have I mean overall growth is
reasonably good uh growth is of course
led by the pricing as well as uh some
kind of volume growth yet uh the claims
ratio at the aggregate level of course
if you go segment by segment there could
be some difference but at a aggregate
level CLE still inching up now is this
an outcome of you know just the claims
inflation or also you know claims
frequency also sort
of reflecting some kind of a uh increase
year in years so good question thank
you yeah so
aash I think on the first one on the
commercial lines uh pretty much in line
with what you mentioned which is
primarily whatever you see as change in
the loss ratios whether it is for fire
engineering or some of the key
commercial lines the large part of the
change in the loss experience is
predominantly driven by the impact that
we have seen on account of flood events
uh so so and this year unfortunately if
you would have seen which is what we put
out also as a part of the opening
transcript I think the aggregate impact
that we have seen on account of various
catastrophic events last year was about
28 cror this year if you look at 9
months we are already that number is at
about 137 crores a large part of it is
of course some of the commercial lines
but maybe the recent Chennai floods I
would also say we have also got a
reasonably large number of claims that
is coming on the retail side which is
more on the motor side of the business
as well but to stay with on the
commercial lines I think the large part
of the the loss ratio change is
predominant driven by the impact that we
have seen on account of uh the various
flood events that we have seen and not
because of uh any other reason in fact
uh the overall growth in the commercial
lines particularly on fire has pretty
much played out in line with what we
have been seeking even in the earlier
quarters as in to say that the price
drop consequent to the removal of the
iip rate has been broadly in that range
of 5 to 7% and which was largely offset
I would say by the increase in the
reinsurance rates that we had seen at
the time of negotiating the program at
the beginning of the year so hence to
that extent is where I think our the
growth for the overall Market has been
largely muted in line with what we spoke
even during the April call uh what will
happen in the next year reinsurance
renewal program I think uh maybe I think
we will be able to come back with a much
better Insight when we announce numbers
on a full year basis in April because
that's the time when we would have
largely concluded the reinsurance
placements but otherwise on so far as
the attritional losses are concerned I
think there is nothing other than re
some of the impact on catastrophic
losses uh related numbers to your second
point on the health loss ratio I think
is it's pretty much which is why I think
in response to one of the earlier uh
earlier questions that had come through
is where we had kind of put out the
breakdown of the L
issues so so in that sense there if you
clearly see I think the loss ratios are
pretty much in line with the range that
we are comfortable with which is just to
kind of rate rate group Heth loss ratios
we have generally spoken about it being
in the range of 94 95% that's the number
at which we have ended even the current
N9 month numbers and Retail health inity
I think the range that we have spoken
about has been between 65 to 70% if you
would have looked at the the N9 month
numbers again they pretty much in line
with the range that we have spoken about
um of course we do see inflation uh uh
and let's say possibly at times increase
in claim frequency particularly let's
say during Quarter Two largely driven by
monsoons and other related
seasonality but that's something again
like what I mentioned on motor where we
actively engage in kind of driving the
PPN initiatives uh on the motor site for
example we would obviously want to drive
a large part of the motor accidents to a
preferred network of garages the same
thought process is what we have even on
the health side which is to kind of we
have a separate Network management team
which significantly looks at focusing on
driving a lot more traffic to a
preferred network of hospitals where we
are not only able to guarantee so far as
the policy holders are concerned quality
of care which is very very important for
us and more importantly an outcome which
is let's say a possible reduction in the
average claim site and thereby which is
how we are able to to kind of manage the
possible change that we see on inflation
SL frequency and but on an overall basis
I think we're comfortable at the range
at which the loss experiences is playing
out okay thank
you thank
you the next question is from the line
of supratim data from Ambit Capital
please go
ahead thanks for the opportunity my
first question is on the new strategy of
one is one team so could you help me
understand what would be the impact on
the top line from this strategy and what
would be the would this also have a cost
impact in the form of cost savings
that's my first question my second
question is on the reinsurance so
globally if we see the reinsurance rates
uh you know this year at first gen has
gone up somewhere between 30 to 50% what
are we expecting here in India given F
you know cy23 so on number of netcat
events which were higher than what we
had seen in
cy22 so that's my second question and
lastly I would just like to understand
kindly that now that you know the growth
has returned on the motor side what is
the market share that you have now
within you know the uh Private Car
segment or the two- wheeler segment and
the commercial vehicle segment if if you
could that a choice thank okay sure so
on the uh uh one one team part in terms
of the top line as well as the cost I
think it will get em what gopal said we
combined issue and what we are able to
deliver as a team uh we have taken
certain initiations in terms of what we
have done
structurally if be the early days for us
to quantify anything of that to the
market you will see that getting
exhibited in time to come we believe
that we rather do it than announce that
this is what we believe uh will get
transpired but clearly what I can assure
you is we do believe there is a kicker
available as on the top line as well as
bottom line on account of what we are
puring as a team so that's where it is
on the reinsurance part I ask goal to
just give an update we don't expect the
premiums to run away we do have a
guideline we say 5 to 7 7 and half%
thereabout is what we expect to come in
but it will all get probably called out
in specific over quarter four goal yeah
yeah so I think just to kind of suim I
think as I said so I think we are in the
midst of the negotiations in so far as
renewing the reinsurance program is
concerned and as I mentioned I think we
will be able to give you a much better
Insight when we kind of announce numbers
for the April uh April call uh is when
we would have stitched in the
reinsurance uh program and the rates for
the next year but the initial indication
seems to kind of unlike last year where
we had seen a significant increase in
the cost of reinsurance for protecting
the uh the uh net retentions or let's
say the XL cost that we have seen for
protecting catastrophic uh event related
losses our sense is obviously the hike
may not be as much as what we had seen
last year exact numbers I think as I
said I will come we will be able to come
back and give you much better Clarity
when we announce numbers in April that's
on the re Insurance side to your point
on market shares within let's say the
new market share for private car and two
wheelers private car we have a market
share of roughly about 12% around that
range and on two wheelers the new market
share has been currently in the range of
about 22% this of course is slightly
lower than what we would have normally
had I mean in the past maybe our market
share could the private car start would
have been Higher by almost about 3 4%
and even on two wheer almost at a
similar level I mean would have been we
have always been saying that on on new
two wheelers one in four uh one in four
two wheer sales is a a policy of is
lomard so to that extent this is pretty
much in line with what we have seen over
the last two years where we have lost a
market share but as sanjie indicated I
think the momentum for us as we speak
looks to be very very strong and
positive and which is why if you look at
some of the quarter three or month of
December numbers the Head Start that
we're getting into in Q4 and thereafter
seems to be very very positive for us
and that's what we are very optimistic
and hence to that extent uh even in the
earlier earnings call if you recollect
what we had said was uh motor we should
see on an aggregate basis growth coming
back uh in line with the market the
early Trend seems to indicate that in
fact for the month of December just to
rate we have actually had an
outperformance relative to the industry
growth of
8.8% thank
you thank
you ladies and gentlemen due to poity of
time we will now take the last question
from the line of Ashish Sharma from enam
as ass Management Company please go
ahead yeah hi uh thanks for the
opportunity uh uh just one question on
on similarly on the combined ratio uh
given that we are trending better than
uh uh uh in terms of improvement in
Combined ratio uh so can I mean if if as
you mentioned that you will take another
quarter sort before you would want to
change the guidance but just wondering
now is there a possibility now that the
business can operate at a combined ratio
of 100% or below I mean given that we
seeing some sort of
a so I think fair question as from your
perspective but I think stand one we'll
discuss this early by next qus to where
we are see because we still won be
overall trend coming out in a consolid
we don't want to J the gun while the
early signs do look better for us but
the sort of opportunity that we have as
a company we will continue to invest so
I would be very honest uh that uh
science investment we can be where we
are
but and the industry combined overall
still at 112% so you know there are
structural changes and my firm belief is
which I can Shar with you uh we would
love to see industry itself improving in
a significant way because today well
industry is very they able to perform at
X the whole industry improv structurally
I don't see any reason why IC Lombard
can drive far better benefit out of it
so we are operating both industry level
as well as the company level uh to make
an impact uh but uh for a company like
us and the opportunity which I said in
my opening remarks again is significant
so we would definitely use some
percentage of what comes our way to
reinvest to ensure that we have Future
Ready in terms of the opportunity that
comes would not jump the gun to call out
and say 100 is what it is it will be a
mix of things help will continue to seek
more investment from us because we have
reasonable competition as well as
opportunity you know being made
available to us uh and similarly on the
digital space we'll continue to do what
is required to harness our own uh
ambition or may we want to be so with
all that in mind
uh I don't want to you know close out
seeing that is what it would be but
let's discuss this when we are there on
the April in the
call
thank you yes yes ladies and gentlemen
due to paity of time that would be the
last question for today I now hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir uh I
think uh thanks so much I think the call
has gone beyond the distance but
absolutely enjoyed interacting with each
one of you and look forward to uh uh
catching up with each one of you in time
to come we stay positive and we do
believe that we have a great set of
colleagues operating in this segment
with very very extensive experience and
we would definitely do what is required
to you know add further value to the
company in terms of the industry which
gives us tremendous opportunity thank
you so much and have a great 2024 and
see you
soon thank you on behalf of ICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited that
concludes this conference thank you all
for joining us you may now disconnect
your
lines